Hello friends, I am Dr. Ved Prakash
Mishra your Anorectal Surgeon
welcome you to my YouTube channel.  We have
started a series on
what methods are used in the treatment of piles or hemorrhoids
?  In this sequence, today I want to tell you what
you might have often heard that
piles can be cured with one vaccine.  What is the
treatment of piles in one shot?  You have to understand that nothing
else is done in this.  There is an injection
called pilonidic acid, a
sclerizing agent, which is
injected under the mucosa at the base of the hemorrhoid.  Due to which the supply gets
hampered and the piles
warts dry up.  Fibrosis occurs there.
Fibrosis occurs at its base.
So the piles warts gradually dry up.
This is what is called
treatment of piles in one vaccine.  This is basically an injection
procedure.  Some people use this regularly.
But we use it only when the
patient cannot undergo a surgical procedure.
In that condition, we use it to stop the blood and dry the brain.
Many surgeons use it in the vas deferens.
Nowadays its latest use is to
make a form and use it, that is, to
form that liquid and
inject a little of it.  Therefore, less amount has to be deposited.
You have to keep in mind that whenever you
think about injection therapy,
get it done only by a skilled doctor because
it has its own complications.  If it is
not administered at the right place or the dose is excessive, then it becomes a
big problem which can lead to
analginosis and this is a
big complication. Sometimes the patient
comes to us and says that he had got an injection but there is a
lot of problem in getting it blocked, then
this is analginosis and there is
more fibrosis, so whenever you
think about injection therapy, then get it done by any skilled
doctor who is regular and has knowledge about it.
Thank you.